<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pragati V. Prasad</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pragati V. Prasad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Next Dose: July 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>/news/news-july23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-july23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus &amp;amp; vaccine news…
We’re seeing some worrisome trends regarding childhood immunizations. There was plenty of concern about this during height of the pandemic. The Director-General of the World Health Organization is encouraged by increasing childhood vaccinations in some countries, but almost 50% of countries that saw declines are not improving, according to the United Nations. The US is still grappling with kids being behind on vaccines, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Year 1 Update: Progress is my first name (actually)</title>
      <link>/posts/phd-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/phd-2/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year since I started my PhD!!! I&amp;rsquo;m so excited to call myself a 2nd year PhD student soon. Here, I&amp;rsquo;d like to assess what I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished, how I&amp;rsquo;ve felt about it, and lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Revisiting this graphic. The only thing missing here is that there is a line for each requirement and project, overlapping each other, with several Vallies of Despair aligning at the same point in time 😅 I would like to say that I am firmly in Phase 4 for a number of projects, which is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2023 Viral &amp; Vaccine News</title>
      <link>/news/news-june23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-june23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus and vaccine news… arboviruses are on the rise.
It was expected with summers becoming hotter and extreme weather phenomena occurring more frequently, but the devastation does not indicate that those who expected it were able to put money into preparedness. Dengue in Peru has all-time high severity for South American dengue outbreaks this year, according to NPR.
This is especially problematic due to the concept of original antigenic sin: dengue has four distinct (sero)types, and having mild illness from a prior infection by one serotype can lead to a more severe illness (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2023 Viral &amp; Vaccine News</title>
      <link>/news/news-jan23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-jan23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus and vaccine news…
 China’s lifting of COVID-19 restrictions is being monitored abroad. Several other countries are following suit in loosening COVID-19 mitigations: Hong Kong, Japan, Spain, Italy, and South Korea. Israel and EU conduct independent reviews of Pfizer vaccine and don’t find a link to strokes. Uganda announces the end of recent Ebola epidemic.  United Nations January 03: COVID-19: China infection surge on agenda at WHO coronavirus meeting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2022 Published Pandemic Modelling Literature</title>
      <link>/posts/modelling-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/modelling-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of December 2022 published pandemic modelling literature. There’s a lot of commentary on mathematical models and their pitfalls as it pertains to pandemic science this month.
I searched “pandemic mathematical modelling” on PubMed, filtering between 12/01/2022 and 12/31/2022, on December 24, 2022, which resulted in 47 journal articles. This I reviewed titles and abstracts of each of the 47 articles to only include papers about transmission models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Models Were Used in the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>/posts/modelling-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/modelling-1/</guid>
      <description>While mathematical models themselves have proved to be interesting to dissect, it&amp;rsquo;s really important to understand the process by which they are used in decision-making. The COVID-19 pandemic has documented this in great detail, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing some peer-reviewed articles that might be particularly useful in understanding how models were used in the pandemic.
In April of 2020, Panovska-Griffiths asks the question &amp;ldquo;Can mathematical modeling solve the current Covid-19 crisis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting my PhD!</title>
      <link>/posts/phd-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/phd-1/</guid>
      <description>I quit my job this month and am starting my PhD in Epidemiology.
This has been a long time coming My main motivation has always been to work on healthcare/public health problems and using computational techniques to achieve that, but it took me awhile to find the right avenue.
I started off as a computational biologist in 2015. After two years of developing antibody modeling software, I decided to study population-level health and started a masters degree in epidemiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model 2: A Chikungunya Model</title>
      <link>/posts/model-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/model-2/</guid>
      <description>A majority of my work so far has been in respitatory viruses and HIV, so developing models for vector-borne viruses is a fun challenge for me. Here, we have my take on a Chikungunya (CHIKV) model developed by Yakob &amp;amp; Clements for the 2006 Réunion Island outbreak.
I try a couple of different versions of the model to try to replicate the results here. This post is a short example of the process that goes into model development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Pragati and I am an epidemiologist.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently a 1st year PhD student. I have a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from the University of Texas at Austin and a Master of Public Health in Epidemiology from Emory University. I worked for 3 years at CDC as an ORISE Fellow / Health Scientist and for 2 years as a Scientific Software Developer prior to my masters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model 1: A Simple Dengue Model</title>
      <link>/posts/model-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/model-1/</guid>
      <description>The following is my rendition of a 2018 Kong et al. model for the 2014 dengue (DENV) outbreak in Guangzhou, China using EpiModel.
I developed the SEIR-SEI model described by Kong et al., where SEIR respresents the human compartments and SEI represents the vector compartments. The total infections for this outbreak depending on transmission heterogeneity (kappa) ranges between 558,000 and 10 million (Table 1). This illustrates the importance of accounting for dispersion (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback &amp; Sign-up Form</title>
      <link>/signup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/signup/</guid>
      <description> Loading…  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
