<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pragati V. Prasad</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pragati V. Prasad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Models Were Used in the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>/posts/modeling-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/modeling-1/</guid>
      <description>While mathematical models themselves have proved to be interesting to dissect, it&amp;rsquo;s really important to understand the process by which they are used in decision-making. The COVID-19 pandemic has documented this in great detail, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing some peer-reviewed articles that might be particularly useful in understanding how models were used in the pandemic.
In April of 2020, Panovska-Griffiths asks the question &amp;ldquo;Can mathematical modeling solve the current Covid-19 crisis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting my PhD!</title>
      <link>/posts/phd-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/phd-1/</guid>
      <description>I quit my job this month and am starting my PhD in Epidemiology.
This has been a long time coming My main motivation has always been to work on healthcare/public health problems and using computational techniques to achieve that, but it took me awhile to find the right avenue.
I started off as a computational biologist in 2015. After two years of developing antibody modeling software, I decided to study population-level health and started a masters degree in epidemiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model 2: A Chikungunya Model</title>
      <link>/posts/model-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/model-2/</guid>
      <description>A majority of my work so far has been in respitatory viruses and HIV, so developing models for vector-borne viruses is a fun challenge for me. Here, we have my take on a Chikungunya (CHIKV) model developed by Yakob &amp;amp; Clements for the 2006 Réunion Island outbreak.
I try a couple of different versions of the model to try to replicate the results here. This post is a short example of the process that goes into model development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Pragati and I am an epidemiologist. I&amp;rsquo;m currently a PhD student.
In an effort to deepen my scientific capabilities, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting my adaptions of published infectious disease models in Posts. You may find some other modelling and epidemiology content there as well.
I have a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from the University of Texas at Austin and a Master of Public Health in Epidemiology from Emory University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model 1: A Simple Dengue Model</title>
      <link>/posts/model-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/model-1/</guid>
      <description>The following is my rendition of a 2018 Kong et al. model for the 2014 dengue (DENV) outbreak in Guangzhou, China using EpiModel.
I developed the SEIR-SEI model described by Kong et al., where SEIR respresents the human compartments and SEI represents the vector compartments. The total infections for this outbreak depending on transmission heterogeneity (kappa) ranges between 558,000 and 10 million (Table 1). This illustrates the importance of accounting for dispersion (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
