<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Pragati V. Prasad</title>
    <link>/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Pragati V. Prasad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Next Dose: July 2023</title>
      <link>/news/news-july23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-july23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus &amp;amp; vaccine news…
We’re seeing some worrisome trends regarding childhood immunizations. There was plenty of concern about this during height of the pandemic. The Director-General of the World Health Organization is encouraged by increasing childhood vaccinations in some countries, but almost 50% of countries that saw declines are not improving, according to the United Nations. The US is still grappling with kids being behind on vaccines, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2023 Viral &amp; Vaccine News</title>
      <link>/news/news-june23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-june23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus and vaccine news… arboviruses are on the rise.
It was expected with summers becoming hotter and extreme weather phenomena occurring more frequently, but the devastation does not indicate that those who expected it were able to put money into preparedness. Dengue in Peru has all-time high severity for South American dengue outbreaks this year, according to NPR.
This is especially problematic due to the concept of original antigenic sin: dengue has four distinct (sero)types, and having mild illness from a prior infection by one serotype can lead to a more severe illness (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2023 Viral &amp; Vaccine News</title>
      <link>/news/news-jan23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/news-jan23/</guid>
      <description>This month in virus and vaccine news…
 China’s lifting of COVID-19 restrictions is being monitored abroad. Several other countries are following suit in loosening COVID-19 mitigations: Hong Kong, Japan, Spain, Italy, and South Korea. Israel and EU conduct independent reviews of Pfizer vaccine and don’t find a link to strokes. Uganda announces the end of recent Ebola epidemic.  United Nations January 03: COVID-19: China infection surge on agenda at WHO coronavirus meeting</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
